<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Real Estate Video Blog with Bud &amp; Kristin Gragg</title>
    <description>Serving as Loyal Real Estate Professionals, Building a Legacy of Integrity, REAL Relationships, and Positively Outrageous Customer Service, WHILE HAVING FUN!</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:41:53 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 12:41:53 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is All That Gobbledygook Behind Our Names?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/n3FDI8uNoO4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We hold many different titles and designations. Here&amp;rsquo;s what they all mean.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Have you ever noticed all of the titles that Kristin and I have behind our names? Titles like ABR, CSA, CNE, RCSD, etc. Today I just wanted to give you a quick overview of all the designations that we hold and how earning them has allowed us to develop our wide breadth of real estate knowledge:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Certified Residential Specialist (CRS)&lt;/strong&gt; means that we’re specialists in the residential realm of real estate sales.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graduate, Realtor Institute (GRI)&lt;/strong&gt; means that we know how to handle everything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E-PRO&lt;/strong&gt; is a designation that means we are up to date on all the latest real estate technology and know-how to use it to help ourselves and our clients.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABR&lt;/strong&gt; stands for Accredited Buyer’s Representative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=All these titles show how much we care about helping our clients succeed.%20http://localhost:4000/what-is-all-that-gobbledygook-behind-our-names.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“All these titles show how much we care about helping our clients succeed.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CSA&lt;/strong&gt; stands for Certified Staging Advocate. This is all about preparing your home like a product for sale. Little details matter, and we know which ones matter most.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CNE&lt;/strong&gt; stands for Certified Negotiation Expert and &lt;strong&gt;MCNE&lt;/strong&gt; stands for Master Certified Negotiation Experts. These are two designations that we’ve earned in the art of the deal. Using tactics and leveraging market conditions to your benefit is what we do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broker&lt;/strong&gt;. This is one of our fundamental designations. Anybody can pass the real estate licensing exam, but a broker has taken it to the next level with an additional 90 hours of training and another state exam. I’ve been a broker for over 20 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RCS-D&lt;/strong&gt; is our newest designation. It stands for Real Estate Collaborative Specialist- Divorce. To put that simply, it means we have been trained to handle this specific type of real estate situation dealing with a divorcing or divorced couple. There are a lot of pitfalls to be wary of in a situation like this, but we know how to handle them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of these titles and designations are our way of showing you how much we care about representing you to the best of our abilities no matter your situation. If you or someone you know wants to buy, sell, or invest in real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out via phone or email today. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-is-all-that-gobbledygook-behind-our-names.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-is-all-that-gobbledygook-behind-our-names.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Comparing the Market in 2005 vs. 2020</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/cu3ErGLDMxI?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m sharing the differences between the real estate market in 2005 and 2020.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Today I’m discussing 2005 versus 2020. Recently, we were asked by a buyer if she should wait until the market crash is over to buy a home. She believed wholeheartedly that we were headed for a market crash. About a year ago, I did a market update concerning the real estate market here in the Valley and we anticipated a bit of a slowdown in 2019. However, guess what? I was wrong. 2019 saw interest rates below 4%, which boosted the economy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There’s a consensus out there that a recession is imminent&lt;/strong&gt; and there will be another downturn in the market in 2020. Times have changed, and there are quite a few differences between the years 2005 and 2020. At the end of 2019, U.S. unemployment is at 3.5%, the lowest it’s been since June 1953. When adjusted for inflation, today’s home prices are lower than at the peak of 2006, which contributed to the crash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subprime and non-prime mortgage lending are at record lows—less than 5% in today’s market, as compared to 20% in 2005. That was the single biggest difference in the real estate market crash of 2006 to 2007. Today, there are stricter lending guidelines and standards, reducing the likelihood of borrowers defaulting on their mortgages. Today, homebuyers are more cautious, and they’re electing to retain equity in their homes instead of borrowing against them, as in the disaster of 2005.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=2019 saw interest rates below 4%, which boosted the economy.%20http://localhost:4000/comparing-the-market-in-2005-vs-2020.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“2019 saw interest rates below 4%, which boosted the economy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a strong, steady, appreciating market, as opposed to a fast peak and a quick valley. Keep in mind that, nationwide, there are different markets and different stories. Here in Phoenix, 202 people a day are still moving to Maricopa County. &lt;strong&gt;Businesses are relocating here in droves&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any real estate needs, even just a referral for a vendor, get in touch with us by phone or email. We would love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2020 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/comparing-the-market-in-2005-vs-2020.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/comparing-the-market-in-2005-vs-2020.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Gratitude Pie Party Extravaganza</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4Il4Aw_gsns?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some of the great photos that we took and wanted to share from our Thanksgiving pie event.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;It was so great to be able to see so many of you at our recent Thanksgiving pie event, and whether you were able to attend or not, &lt;strong&gt;we hope you all have a very happy holiday and a happy New Year&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions regarding real estate, don’t hesitate to reach out. We’d love to help you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/lBF-_9lZOxQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/gratitude-pie-party-extravaganza.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gratitude-pie-party-extravaganza.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Would You Be Better Off Buying Rental Properties or a New Boat?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7VI7-DsReYA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;What can you gain by investing in real estate? Let me tell you a quick story to answer this question.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;To illustrate the benefits of real estate investing, I want to tell you a quick story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all starts about 22 years ago when we were living in a subdivision in Mountain Park Ranch (my “office” was the front of my house). One day a neighbor visited us and said she’d been saving money for three or four years so she could buy a boat for her family. She had between $45,000 and $50,000 in the bank, and she was ready to pull the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s when she asked, “Should I pay cash for this boat?” We took a second to think about it and said no. Then we told her what we’d do instead—and what we recommended she should do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We told her to take that $50,000 and use it to buy two rental properties&lt;/strong&gt; (3 bedrooms, 2 bathrooms, a 2-car garage, 1,600 square feet, etc.) worth roughly $200,000 at 10% down. Financing was about 6% to 7% at the time, which made the mortgage payments about $1,000 to $1,100 per month. If you were to rent these properties at $1,300 to $1,500, that would mean a cash flow of $300 per month for each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, if she were to use financing to purchase the boat for, say, $40,000 at an amortization timeline of 80 months, that would cost $400 per month. With the $600 in cash flow, she’d be able to cover the boat payment with $200 to spare for gas, repairs, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Sure enough, the next day we watched as she came home and backed her new boat into her driveway.%20http://localhost:4000/would-you-be-better-off-buying-rental-properties-or-a-new-boat.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Sure enough, the next day we watched as she came home and backed her new boat into her driveway.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By doing this, her tenants would be paying for both of the mortgages on her properties and the boat&lt;/strong&gt;. What’s more, those properties would each be worth about $400,000 today. That would give her $800,000 in real estate assets, and they would more or less be paid off at this time. Not to mention all the tax benefits she could take advantage of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent about an hour laying out this scenario to her. Sure enough, the next day we watched as she came home and backed her new boat into her driveway. That’s right—she used the cash to buy the boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, not everyone has the stomach to be a landlord, and we’re still dear friends with this neighbor. We’ve even been on her boat a few times. To her credit, she’s used it a lot over the years, which is what you should do with assets that depreciate over time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like to talk more about investing in residential real estate and how it could benefit you, don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We’d love to hear from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/would-you-be-better-off-buying-rental-properties-or-a-new-boat.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/would-you-be-better-off-buying-rental-properties-or-a-new-boat.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Way to Refer Us</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Q_8eOxPkAtY?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;We wanted to quickly let you know the best way to refer us to your friends and family.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you so much for your referrals over the years! &lt;strong&gt;We cannot tell you how grateful we are for you and all that you’ve done for us&lt;/strong&gt;. This is an extension of the last blog post we did about referring us. Feel free to &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://budandkristin.com/let-us-be-your-trusted-referral-source.html&quot;&gt;watch that video here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today’s message is about referring us the correct way. We just want to ask you a tiny favor about referring us. After you have recommended us, please don’t just give them our business card or tell them our information. What we would like you to say is: “Do you mind if I have Bud and Kristin call you?” Then send us their contact information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This way, they’ll be expecting our phone call. That’s the way we can effectively communicate with them. There are countless times that we’ve heard from you, our past clients, that you told someone about us (which is great!), but we never hear from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Please don’t just give someone our business card.%20http://localhost:4000/the-best-way-to-refer-us.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Please don’t just give someone our business card.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We ask that you let us contact them so that we can take care of them the way we’ve taken care of you in the past&lt;/strong&gt;. There’s no pressure. It doesn’t matter whether they’re buying or selling even two years from now—we’re never going to pressure anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We greatly appreciate all of you for what you’ve done for us. Thank you! If you ever have any questions concerning real estate, please feel free to reach out to us by phone or email. We would love to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-best-way-to-refer-us.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-best-way-to-refer-us.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Let Us Be Your Trusted Referral Source</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_btqvZvdsP4?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s what we can do for anyone you know buying or selling a home.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been in the real estate business for over 25 years, and it never ceases to amaze me when people don’t realize that we’re their trusted source for referrals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you or anyone you know moving from the Phoenix metropolitan area to anywhere else in the world? Call us. &lt;strong&gt;For outgoing referrals, we have a network of amazing agents all over the globe who we’ll contact on your behalf&lt;/strong&gt;. We’ll vet them, interview them, and set you up with an experienced Realtor who will help you. During this process, we make it a point to keep in touch with you and share our insight. We also handle incoming referrals—meaning anyone moving to the Phoenix metropolitan area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to that, we handle referrals for buyers and sellers even if they aren’t moving to or from the Phoenix area. Just two months ago, I handled a referral for a beachfront property in Panama.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=No matter where they’re moving, we’ll take great care of your friends and family.%20http://localhost:4000/let-us-be-your-trusted-referral-source.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“No matter where they’re moving, we’ll take great care of your friends and family.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter where they’re moving, we’ll take great care of your friends and family, so don’t hesitate to give us a call and let us be your referral source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or have any real estate needs, call or email me anytime. I’d love to speak with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/let-us-be-your-trusted-referral-source.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/let-us-be-your-trusted-referral-source.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Elephant in the Room</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Mo07aqVg77s?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tired of going through the hassle of selling your home on the market? Try this solution!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to &lt;strong&gt;skip the hassle of selling your home this fall&lt;/strong&gt;, we have a new option for you: We can get an offer on your home from companies who want to buy it, instead of individuals on the traditional market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you call, just let us know whether you prefer &lt;strong&gt;maximum value&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;maximum convenience&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’ll close quickly and get equity from your home in as little as seven days&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You pick your closing date&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No showings or open houses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No negotiating with buyers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Skip the cost, time, and (in some cases) embarrassment of getting your home market-ready&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freedom to move on your own timeline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No strangers and Realtors walking through your home&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No risk of two mortgage payments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=We can get an offer on your home from companies who want to buy it, instead of individuals on the traditional market.%20http://localhost:4000/the-elephant-in-the-room.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“We can get an offer on your home from companies who want to buy it, instead of individuals on the traditional market.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re interested in an instant offer on your home, &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;http://unbouncepages.com/bud-gragg-guaranteed-offer/&quot;&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll go to our investor relationships and companies who specialize in all this and secure the best offer for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can likely get you an offer in seven days without any hassles on your part showing your home to the public. If you’re interested in this offer, give me a call or text on my cell at (480) 327-8092. We’re here to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-elephant-in-the-room.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-elephant-in-the-room.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Time to Invest in Real Estate Is Now</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/aDQyld_nKO0?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I have a quick message about one of my favorite subjects: real estate investing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you been thinking of investing in real estate to build your wealth? If so, I have good news: I have honestly never seen a better time to invest. It’s a perfect storm here in the Valley; &lt;strong&gt;interest rates have never been lower&lt;/strong&gt;, and there are rumors that they’re going to edge down a little more. If they do, it’ll be a long-term record; they’ve never been that low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a relevant story:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I own a rental property by Intel in Chandler, and it’s not a fancy, upscale home by any stretch. It’s a Shea Home with three bedrooms, two-and-a-half baths, 2,000 square feet, a loft pool, and a Jacuzzi in the backyard. I fixed it up to look nice and put it on the market about 10 days ago. In just two days, I had over 30 inquiries to rent the property and three applications—I hadn’t even shown the property yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=I have honestly never seen a better time to invest.%20http://localhost:4000/the-time-to-invest-in-real-estate-is-now.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“I have honestly never seen a better time to invest.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This clearly indicates that &lt;strong&gt;demand is through the roof&lt;/strong&gt;. As a landlord, this is very exciting to me because I get to cherry-pick the best tenants. I did a two-year lease and got $2,300 for the place, which is $150 more than the last tenant. The tenant is single and a surgeon, so I’m confident she can afford the place. At $2,300 a month, that comes out to $55,000 I made when I signed that lease. Sure, I’m paying the principal, interest, taxes, and insurance on the property, but &lt;strong&gt;I’ve got $700 to $800 cash flow that I can channel towards the principal to pay the property down over the course of 10 years&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if you’ve ever thought about investing in real estate here in the Valley, reach out to me. I would love to help you create wealth like I have done with so many others in real estate, including myself. There are all different types of properties to invest in for different reasons, and we can discuss which would be right for your goals. Hope to hear from you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-time-to-invest-in-real-estate-is-now.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-time-to-invest-in-real-estate-is-now.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Moving? Don’t Forget These Important Steps</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/QsXO5e3mP1E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re about to move, follow this checklist to ensure a smooth transition.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving can be stressful, but remembering to follow a few important steps can make it much less so. There are several things people often forget when moving, and today we’ll be highlighting just a few. The next time you pack your bags to head to a new home, always make sure to complete these crucial tasks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Determine if you’ll need to switch banks&lt;/strong&gt;. Unless your old bank happens to have a branch near your new home, you may need to switch banks entirely. This may be tedious, but you’ll be glad you did it once you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Find a new healthcare provider and pharmacy&lt;/strong&gt;. Calling your current doctor to have prescriptions transferred to a pharmacy near your new home will give you plenty of time to search for a new healthcare provider after you’ve moved in. Of course, you should still keep the contact information for your old doctor so that you can have paperwork and medical recorders forwarded once you’ve got a new provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Transfer your memberships to local clubs or gyms&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Request records from your children’s school(s)&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, you can take these records with you to their new school district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Raid the kitchen&lt;/strong&gt;. About a month before you move, start thawing out and using the food you’ve had sitting in your freezer and refrigerator so that they are clean and empty before moving day.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Get your car checked up&lt;/strong&gt;. Your vehicle should be in good working order before you make the trip to your new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Transfer your utilities&lt;/strong&gt;. Electricity, gas, trash collection, internet, and all other utilities will need to be canceled and/or transferred.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/moving-dont-forget-these-important-steps.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/moving-dont-forget-these-important-steps.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Long Will It Take Your House to Sell?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HW00fQRYdCA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;How long does it actually take to sell a house? That&amp;rsquo;s a complicated question.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“How long does it take to sell a house?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, that’s a loaded question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Realtor.com, the average number of days on market across the country is about 65 days. However, there are some different factors that I like to bring up when answering this question for clients:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Location&lt;/strong&gt;. How close are you to a main street or a transportation hub in your town? This can play a huge part in today’s buyer’s decision to purchase your home, and how quickly they do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Price&lt;/strong&gt;. Obviously, you don’t want to overprice your home when you place it on the market. I discussed the dangers of pricing your home too high in a previous video, which you can &lt;u&gt;&lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://budandkristin.com/what-happens-when-you-overprice-your-home.html&quot;&gt;watch here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;. If you do, you’ll shrink the pool of buyers looking at your home, and it could also cause issues with the appraisal if you actually did find a buyer who was willing to pay too much—that’s a topic for another time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Inventory&lt;/strong&gt;. How many homes in your neighborhood are currently up for sale? We’ve seen neighborhoods with no houses for sale, which is ideal because that means there’s no competition. However, we’ve also seen neighborhoods with so many houses for sale that it’s almost impossible to calculate how long it would take to sell your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=If a buyer is offering you a cash deal, then your house can in as few as seven days.%20http://localhost:4000/how-long-will-it-take-your-house-to-sell.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“If a buyer is offering you a cash deal, then your house can in as few as seven days.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. School districts&lt;/strong&gt;. This tends to be a huge factor for buyers, especially those with children. A lot of people visit school rating websites to see what schools are like in an area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Walkability&lt;/strong&gt;. Did you know that fewer and fewer people are driving these days? Walkability is an important criterion for today’s buyers. Is your house somewhere close to coffee shops, grocery stores, restaurants, or nightlife attractions? Having a better walkability score makes your home more marketable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Type of buyer&lt;/strong&gt;. What kinds of buyers are looking to purchase your home? If they’re offering you a cash deal, then your house can close in as few as seven days. Financed buyers like those with FHA or VA loans will take a bit longer. The rule of thumb is to establish a 30-day close of escrow once you get a buyer with a loan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about selling a home or real estate in general, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. We’re here to be your resource.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-long-will-it-take-your-house-to-sell.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-long-will-it-take-your-house-to-sell.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
