<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Real Estate Video Blog with Bud &amp; Kristin Gragg</title>
    <description>Our mission at eXp Realty is to be your best resource for real estate advice. Whether you are a buyer, seller, or investor, our team of professionals can answer any questions you might have about real estate. If you are looking to buy or sell a home, you can get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from The eXp Realty, your professional Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 14:11:03 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2019 14:11:03 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.7.4</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>An Update for Home Sellers</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3u79cSIIUOg?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;The market has changed a bit, but can sellers still get a great price for their home? Let&amp;rsquo;s find out.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’ll be taking a quick look at how our current market affects sellers in particular.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Phoenix market is still favoring sellers over buyers, but not as much as it was at the beginning of 2018. This year’s supply is 34% below normal—only slightly better than last year’s supply, which was 36% below the mark. &lt;strong&gt;As buyers face affordability issues and concerns about an overvalued market, demand continues to shift&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this time last year, demand was 1% above normal. Now, it’s 13% below normal. Though it may feel like a buyer’s market when compared to the last few years, Phoenix is still very much a seller’s market—it’s just a little weaker than last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Phoenix is still very much a seller’s market—it’s just a little weaker than last year.%20http://localhost:4000/an-update-for-home-sellers.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Phoenix is still very much a seller’s market—it’s just a little weaker than last year.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s still more demand than there is supply, but multiple-offer situations will no longer be the norm, and there will likely be fewer sales overall. Depending on interest rates, demand could change in either direction. &lt;strong&gt;As of now, though, buyers and sellers still have some good opportunities in the market&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or would like further information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/an-update-for-home-sellers.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/an-update-for-home-sellers.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What Should Buyers Know About Our Market?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/a1iaV5jlI_M?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve got great news for homebuyers in the Phoenix area. There&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity for you in our market right now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we’ve got a quick update for buyers in the real estate market. The January numbers are in and I’m excited to share them with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The average interest rate rose to 4.64% at the end of 2018, which is up 0.69% from a year ago&lt;/strong&gt;. For buyers that purchase a home at the median sale price of $260,000, that’s about $100 more on your monthly mortgage payment from last year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buyers averaged 1,845 sq ft. at this price, which is nearly 100 square feet smaller than the average from a year ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Home prices will continue to rise, but at a slower pace than in the past.%20http://localhost:4000/what-should-buyers-know-about-our-market.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Home prices will continue to rise, but at a slower pace than in the past.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Renting may not be a suitable alternative anymore&lt;/strong&gt;. Single-family homes appreciated by an average of 8.1% and single-family lease payments increased by about 8.6%, as well. Buying is still a better option over renting, even if it’s just to stabilize your monthly housing expenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Home prices will continue to rise in the first half of 2019, but at a slower rate than in years past. You might see a little more negotiation on the seller’s behalf for closing costs, concessions, etc. &lt;strong&gt;This is good news for buyers overall&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to buy a home here in the Phoenix area, we are the only call you’ll ever need to make. If you have any questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-should-buyers-know-about-our-market.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/what-should-buyers-know-about-our-market.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Protect Your Interests When Buying/Selling a Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hcmcEYyWMmw?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re buying or selling a home, the safest way to get started is by calling a Realtor such as myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the safest way to buy and/or sell a home? There are a couple points to be made regarding this question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, &lt;strong&gt;I consider buying a home the safest investment you can make&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s an appreciating asset that allows you to build equity. You can pay down your principal and interest over time and enjoy certain tax benefits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The safest way to actually buy or sell a home is by calling an agent such as myself.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-interests-when-buyingselling-a-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The safest way to actually buy or sell a home is by calling an agent such as myself.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, &lt;strong&gt;the safest way to actually buy or sell a home is by calling an agent such as myself&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you’re finding a property that suits your needs as a buyer or trying to market your home and get the best deal possible as a seller, you need the expertise of a Realtor. I’d love to help you in either case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, if you’re thinking of buying or selling a home or you have any questions about our real estate market, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I look forward to speaking with you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-interests-when-buyingselling-a-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-protect-your-interests-when-buyingselling-a-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check Out These Stats From the 4th Quarter of 2018</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/J_VqOx8oCPA?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are the stats from the fourth quarter of the 2018 real estate market year for the entire Phoenix area.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like the stock market, in real estate, there’s good and bad news to be found on any given day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is some news that isn’t necessarily bad, though it might seem that way for the uncertain: Every single mortgage broker, banker, and financial planner that I know is advising that mortgage interest rates are going to hit 6%, or possibly even higher. This is a no-brainer because there’s really only one way for rates to go (which is up). We’ve been very, very spoiled with interest rates for about the last eight years now, as they’ve been ridiculously low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buyers who are looking to make a home purchase but are currently on the fence should get in touch with me as soon as possible&lt;/strong&gt;—higher interest rates mean more interest costs on your mortgage loan. Generally, higher rates mean less buying power, so the higher the rate, the less home you’ll be able to afford. By waiting, homes that are available right now might not be within your reach if rates go up higher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Higher interest rates also mean that sellers might not be that apt to put their home on the market&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning that there will be less inventory. If they’ve got a locked-in 4% rate, they’re not going to jump at a 6% or 6.5%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Four of the top five cities for job growth in the country are located right here in Maricopa County.%20http://localhost:4000/check-out-these-stats-from-the-4th-quarter-of-2018.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Four of the top five cities for job growth in the country are located right here in Maricopa County.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is that tech companies are blowing up the Valley of Sun. Companies like Intel, American Express, eBay, Uber, Shutterfly, and Infusionsoft all have something in common: They’re either expanding or relocating their entire company here to the Valley. &lt;strong&gt;Every day, at least 202 are moving to Maricopa County&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An analysis that was conducted by ranking the future job-growth projections of 182 cities in the United States came up with &lt;strong&gt;this top five list&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chandler, Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scottsdale, Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;San Francisco, California&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Peoria, Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gilbert, Arizona&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s right! Four of the top five cities for growth are located right here in Maricopa County. And, according to research done by Zillow, Phoenix, Denver, Washington, D.C., Atlanta, Las Vegas, and San Jose will outperform the rest of the United States in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bottom line is that &lt;strong&gt;we are currently living in the strongest economy in the U.S.&lt;/strong&gt;, and we don’t expect that to change for a while. We have seen steep appreciation over the past eight years, so I understand people’s reluctance to act in the market. However, we believe that appreciation will slow down as inventory increases and rates rise. Overall, we are headed toward a more balanced market, which is a good thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this information has been insightful to you. If you’re thinking of buying, selling, or investing in real estate, you only need to reach out to us. Either myself or Kristin would be happy to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/check-out-these-stats-from-the-4th-quarter-of-2018.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/check-out-these-stats-from-the-4th-quarter-of-2018.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Questions From Our V.I.C.'s (Very Important Clients)</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/tnZP_dibj8E?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;em&gt;Today I&amp;rsquo;m answering some of the most common questions that I hear from prospective homebuyers. They offer a unique insight into the mind of today&amp;rsquo;s buyer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently had our pie giveaway and it’s always one of our favorite events of the year. We give away free Thanksgiving pies, have some snacks and libations, and get to talk to a lot of our “VICs” (Very Important Clients). &lt;strong&gt;After getting to talk to so many of you about your lives and about real estate, we wanted to answer a few of the most common questions that we heard from you today&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Having rented for decades, what are the benefits of homeownership other than building equity? If the current market is a seller’s market, is it a good time to buy or should I wait?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, you’re building equity for yourself as well as getting tax benefits from mortgage interest and property taxes. &lt;strong&gt;If you’re renting, you’re giving those benefits to your landlord and not reaping any of them yourself&lt;/strong&gt;. Stop making your landlord rich and get into a property that you’ll live in and build wealth from through the years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our market is currently leveling out.%20http://localhost:4000/questions-from-our-v-i-c-s-very-important-clients.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our market is currently leveling out.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the second part of the question, our market is currently leveling out right now. This is good news for buyers because there is more to choose from. However, mortgage rates are on the rise, so the window of opportunity is closing for buyers to jump off the fence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about real estate or if you’re interested in buying or selling a home in the near future, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Dec 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/questions-from-our-v-i-c-s-very-important-clients.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/questions-from-our-v-i-c-s-very-important-clients.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Simultaneously Buy and Sell Homes</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/hofmFIzFxNc?rel=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center&quot; style=&quot;font-size:20px; font-style:italic;&quot;&gt;
Buying and selling homes simultaneously is entirely possible; you just need some preparation.
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways you can go about buying and selling homes at the same time. You can buy first and then sell, sell first and then buy, or you can conduct a concurrent/simultaneous close of escrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you try any of these options, there are some things you need to know&lt;/strong&gt;. Find out exactly what you can afford in the buying process—getting pre-qualified with a lender is a great first step. You should also determine your home’s value. By doing this, you’ll know how much equity you have and can figure out what you can afford as a down payment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=There are pros and cons to each, but we can help you find the best option for your situation.%20http://localhost:4000/how-to-simultaneously-buy-and-sell-homes.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“There are pros and cons to each, but we can help you find the best option for your situation.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s how the three strategies we listed earlier work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying first&lt;/strong&gt;. By doing this, you can enjoy a pressure-free search without having to worry about selling your current home. You also won’t need interim housing and can move without any rush. However, you may be having to pay two mortgages temporarily and you won’t know how much equity you have for the down payment on your new home. We’re good at getting a close estimate, but the exact amount is unknown.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling first&lt;/strong&gt;. With this option, you’ll know the equity you have for a new house and you won’t have to pay two mortgages at the same time. You may need interim housing for when you’re without a home. We can even negotiate a leaseback with the buyer of your current home.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying and selling simultaneously&lt;/strong&gt;. This is doable, but it takes a good amount of planning and flexibility. For example, home inspections and appraisals must be done as soon as possible to get the ball rolling. Thankfully, If your buyer isn’t pressured to move in right away, you’re less pressured to find a home immediately. Or, the buyer can close escrow and allow you to rent the home in the meantime.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are pros and cons to each, but we can help you find the best option for your situation. If you’d like some guidance, have questions, or need information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-simultaneously-buy-and-sell-homes.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/how-to-simultaneously-buy-and-sell-homes.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
