<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Global Real Estate Podcast with Bud & Kristin Gragg</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from eXp Realty - your professional Phoenix Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Bud & Kristin Gragg</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2018-12-11 09:23:21 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Bud & Kristin Gragg</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>BudGragg@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Bud & Kristin Gragg</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Bud & Kristin Gragg</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Phoenix Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from eXp Realty - your professional Phoenix Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Simultaneously Buy and Sell Homes</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-simultaneously-buy-and-sell-homes.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Bud & Kristin Gragg</author>
        <pubDate>2018-11-29 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Bud+Gragg/Videos/Bud+and+Kristin+Gragg+-+How+to+Simultaneously+Buy+and+Sell+Homes.mp4</guid>
        <description>


Buying and selling homes simultaneously is entirely possible; you just need some preparation.

 

There are a few ways you can go about buying and selling homes at the same time. You can buy first and then sell, sell first and then buy, or you can conduct a concurrent/simultaneous close of escrow.

Before you try any of these options, there are some things you need to know. Find out exactly what you can afford in the buying process—getting pre-qualified with a lender is a great first step. You should also determine your home’s value. By doing this, you’ll know how much equity you have and can figure out what you can afford as a down payment.

“There are pros and cons to each, but we can help you find the best option for your situation.”

Here’s how the three strategies we listed earlier work:


  Buying first. By doing this, you can enjoy a pressure-free search without having to worry about selling your current home. You also won’t need interim housing and can move without any rush. However, you may be having to pay two mortgages temporarily and you won’t know how much equity you have for the down payment on your new home. We’re good at getting a close estimate, but the exact amount is unknown.
  Selling first. With this option, you’ll know the equity you have for a new house and you won’t have to pay two mortgages at the same time. You may need interim housing for when you’re without a home. We can even negotiate a leaseback with the buyer of your current home.
  Buying and selling simultaneously. This is doable, but it takes a good amount of planning and flexibility. For example, home inspections and appraisals must be done as soon as possible to get the ball rolling. Thankfully, If your buyer isn’t pressured to move in right away, you’re less pressured to find a home immediately. Or, the buyer can close escrow and allow you to rent the home in the meantime.


There are pros and cons to each, but we can help you find the best option for your situation. If you’d like some guidance, have questions, or need information, feel free to reach out to us. We look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Bud+Gragg/Videos/Bud+and+Kristin+Gragg+-+How+to+Simultaneously+Buy+and+Sell+Homes.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Bud+Gragg/Videos/Bud+and+Kristin+Gragg+-+How+to+Simultaneously+Buy+and+Sell+Homes.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Buying and selling homes simultaneously is entirely possible; you just need some preparation.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Bud & Kristin Gragg</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Buying and selling homes simultaneously is entirely possible; you just need some preparation.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Phoenix, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Bud & Kristin Gragg</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Bud & Kristin Gragg</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from eXp Realty - your professional Phoenix Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
